What is your English level right now?
Let's find out. I'm going to ask you 30
questions. Keep track of how many you
answer correctly and at the end of this
video, you'll know your English CFR
level. Let's get started. The first 10
questions are beginner level. You'll see
three sentences and you should pick the
one that uses English correctly. Ready?
Question one. Mary don't like spicy
food. Mary isn't like spicy food. Mary
doesn't like spicy food.
Mary doesn't like spicy food is correct.
To make a sentence negative in the
simple present tense, we use don't for
I, you, we, and they, and doesn't for
he, she, and it. Mary doesn't like spicy
food. Question two. This book is bigger
than that one. This book is more big
than that one. This book is the biggest
that one.
This book is bigger than that one is
correct. When we compare two things, we
usually add to an adjective. Fast,
faster, big, bigger, easy, easier. But
watch out. If a word has three or more
syllables, we use the word more instead.
Difficult. More difficult. Interesting.
More interesting. Beautiful. More
beautiful. This book is bigger than that
one, but that book is more interesting
than this one. Question three. Paul has
a meeting in Monday. Paul has a meeting
on Monday. Paul has a meeting at Monday.
Paul has a meeting on Monday is correct.
When talking about the days of the week,
we use on Paul has a meeting on Monday.
Question four. I bought a umbrella. I
bought an umbrella. I bought umbrella.
I bought an umbrella is correct. We use
a before words that start with a
consonant sound. A car, a banana, a
house. But we use an before words that
start with a vowel sound. An apple, an
idea, an umbrella. Question five. I
think it rains tonight. I think it will
rain tonight. I think it is raining
tonight.
I think it will rain tonight is correct.
To talk about things that will happen in
the future, we can use the future tense.
Will plus a verb. I will call you
tomorrow. She will arrive next week. I
think it will rain tonight. Question
six. That phone is mine. That phone is
mine. That phone is to me.
If a possessive comes right before a
noun, we say my phone, your phone, his
phone, her phone, our phone, their
phone. But if a possessive isn't
connected to a noun, we say that phone
is mine, is yours, is his, is hers, is
ours, is theirs. Question seven. Did you
saw the movie yesterday? Did you see the
movie yesterday? Have you seen the movie
yesterday?
Did you see the movie yesterday? Is
correct. When we're talking about an
action that happened at a specific time
in the past, like yesterday, we use the
simple past tense. I went, he ate, you
saw. And to make that a question, we use
did plus the base verb. Did you go? Did
he eat? Did you see the movie yesterday?
Question eight. There is some money on
the table. There are some monies on the
table. There is many money on the table.
There is some money on the table is
correct. Money is an uncountable noun
like news or air. So, it's always
singular. And the word many refers to
multiple countable items. many houses or
many people. But we can use some with
both countable and uncountable nouns.
There are some people at the party.
There is some money on the table.
Question nine. Her spoke to him this
morning. She spoke to he this morning.
He spoke to her this morning.
When a pronoun is the subject of a
sentence, we use subject pronouns. I,
you, he, she, we, you, they. And when a
pronoun is the object of a verb or a
preposition, we use object pronouns. Me,
you, him, her, us, them. He spoke to her
this morning. Question 10. They have
lived here for five years.
They have lived here since 5 years. They
have lived here from five years.
They have lived here for 5 years is
correct. We use for to talk about a
whole period of time. They have lived
here for five years. We use since to
talk about a starting point. We have
been friends since 2020. We use until to
talk about an ending point. She works
until 6 p.m. Congratulations. You've now
completed the beginner section of the
test. If you answered seven or more of
those questions correctly, your English
is likely level A1. If you answered nine
or more correctly, you're at least level
A2. And now we'll begin the intermediate
portion of the test. Again, you should
choose the correct sentence. Question
one. [snorts] You must to finish your
homework. You must finishing your
homework. You must finish your homework.
You must finish your homework is
correct. Must is a modal verb like can,
should, will, and might. And when a
modal verb is followed by another verb,
we don't use the infinitive. Instead, we
use the base verb. I can go. We might be
late. You must finish your homework.
Question two. Janet never gives
attention in class. Janet never pays
attention in class. Janet never throws
attention in class.
Janet never pays attention in class is
correct. To pay attention is a
collocation or a pair of words that
often go together in English. And when
someone is listening closely to another
person, we say they are paying
attention. Question three, have you ever
traveled to Asia? Did you ever traveled
to Asia? Have you ever traveled to Asia?
Have you ever traveled to Asia is
correct. We use the present perfect
tense to talk about the past generally.
In other words, when we're not talking
about a specific time in the past. And
the structure is always the same. We say
have or has plus the past participle of
a verb. Has she ever driven a car. Has
he ever played volleyball? Have you ever
traveled to Asia? Question four. If we
walk slowly, we'd be late. If we walk
slowly, we'll be late. If we walk
slowly, we'd have been late.
In this sentence, we have a condition
that could really happen if we walk
slowly. So, we need to use the first
conditional structure, which is if plus
present simple tense followed by an
outcome in the future tense. If she gets
the job, she'll be happy. If he
exercises every day, he'll get stronger.
If we walk slowly, we'll be late.
Question five. Anna speaks English more
fluently than her brother. Anna speaks
English fluent than her brother. Anna
speaks English more fluent than her
brother.
Anna speaks English more fluently than
her brother is correct. In this
sentence, we're comparing how Anna and
her brother speak. And speak is a verb,
so we need an adverb to modify it.
fluently. And we always use the word
more when comparing with an adverb. My
dad drives more carefully than I do. We
can lift the box more easily if we work
together. Question six. To play video
games is my favorite hobby. Playing
video games is my favorite hobby. To
playing video games is my favorite
hobby.
Playing video games is my favorite hobby
is correct. When a verb is the subject
of a sentence, we almost always use the
ing form or the gerant. Reading relaxes
me. Traveling helps people understand
the world. Playing video games is my
favorite hobby. Question seven. My wife
is practically a vegetarian. She hardly
ever eats meat. She hardly never eats
meat. She never hardly eats meat.
She hardly ever eats meat is correct.
Hardly ever is a set phrase in English
and it means to do something very
rarely. We hardly ever watch TV. Maria
hardly ever takes a vacation. My wife
hardly ever eats meat.
Question eight. Angela always says
what's on her mind. She doesn't beat
above the bush, beat around the bush,
beat beyond the bush.
She doesn't beat around the bush is
correct. To beat around the bush is an
idiom that means to avoid saying
something directly. Angela always says
what's on her mind. She doesn't beat
around the bush. Question nine. Paul
should have told his parents sooner.
Paul should have tell his parents
sooner. Paul should have been telling
his parents sooner.
Paul should have told his parents sooner
is correct. We use should have plus a
past participle to criticize someone or
to express a regret. We should have
taken the bus. I should have eaten less.
Paul should have told his parents
sooner. Question 10. Excuse me. Could
you drop off me at the station? Could
you drop me at the station off? Could
you drop me off at the station?
Could you drop me off at the station is
correct. The phrasal verb to drop off
means to take something or someone to a
location. But when phrasal verbs refer
to a pronoun, that pronoun always goes
in the middle. Pick you up. Take it out.
Let us in. Could you drop me off at the
station? Congratulations. You've now
completed the intermediate section of
the test. If you answered seven or more
of those questions correctly, your
English is likely level B1. If you
answered nine or more correctly, you're
probably level B2. And now we'll begin
the advanced section of the test. Good
luck. Question one. Wow, it's boiling
today, isn't it? Wow, it's boiling
today, is it? Wow, it's boiling today.
It is.
It's boiling today, isn't it? is
correct. When the weather is very hot,
English speakers like to say, "It's
boiling." And we use question tags like
isn't it to confirm something with
another person or to make sure it's
true. And to make a question tag, we
always use an auxiliary verb like have,
can, or be in the negative form. You've
seen this movie, haven't you? She can
speak German, can't she? It's boiling
today, isn't it? Question two. The
film's ending was open to interpretation
and more than a little meticulous,
erroneous, ambiguous.
The word ambiguous means unclear or
difficult to pin down. Someone who's
meticulous pays close attention to
detail and something erroneous is
incorrect. Question three. Come next
June, we will have been living here for
a decade. Come next June, we have lived
here for a decade. Come next June, we
will be living here for a decade.
Come next June, we will have been living
here for a decade is correct. The future
perfect continuous will have been
verbing shows the length of an ongoing
action up to a certain point in the
future. Next week, he will have been
working there for 6 months. This fall,
they will have been dating for 5 years.
Come next June, we will have been living
here for a decade. Question four.
Miriam's dream of becoming a famous
singer never quite turned up, panned
out, kicked off.
To pan out means to develop in a
successful way. To turn up means to
appear unexpectedly. And to kick off
means to begin. Question five. To have
wasted two hours, Tom finally started
his essay. He had wasted two hours, Tom
finally started his essay. Having wasted
two hours, Tom finally started his
essay.
We can use having plus a past participle
to express that one action finished
before a second action began. Having
finished our entre, we ordered dessert.
Having spent a year abroad, Sheila
decided to come home. Having wasted two
hours, Tom finally started his essay.
Question six. The website recommends
applying at least 6 months in advance.
The website recommends to apply at least
6 months in advance. The website
recommends that applying at least 6
months in advance.
When a verb is followed by another verb,
the second verb can either be an
infinitive to eat or a gerand eating.
But recommend is always followed by
ajarand. I recommend going. They
recommend trying. The website recommends
applying. Question seven. Nelson Mandela
is such an inspiring individual. Nelson
Mandela is such inspiring an individual.
Nelson Mandela is so an inspiring
individual.
Nelson Mandela is such an inspiring
individual is correct. The word such
modifies a noun or noun phrase. Such a
good movie. Such a clean apartment. Such
an inspiring individual. The word so
modifies an adjective or an adverb. The
movie was so good. This apartment is so
clean. Nelson Mandela is so inspiring.
Question eight. At the end of the trial,
the judge asked the jury, "Have you
placed a verdict? Have you found a
verdict?" "Have you reached a verdict?"
To reach a verdict is another English
collocation and it means that a jury has
decided the outcome of a court case.
Question nine. The bride had a huge
smile on her face. She looked completely
emphatic,
ecstatic,
erratic.
She looked completely ecstatic meaning
very happy is correct. Emphatic comes
from the word emphasis and it means
forceful. She denied the allegations
emphatically and erratic means
unpredictable. Our neighbors behavior
has been a little erratic lately.
Question 10. Whatever challenging the
test might seem, just remember you're
well prepared. Whenever challenging the
well prepared. However challenging the
test might seem, just remember you're
well prepared.
The word however is usually used as a
conjunction meaning but. I like Indian
food. However, I don't eat it very
often. But however can also be an adverb
that means no matter how, as in however
long the flight is, however old that car
looks, however challenging the test
might seem, just remember you're well
prepared. Congratulations. You've now
finished the advanced portion of the
test. If you answered seven or more
questions correctly, your English is
likely at a C1 level. And if you
answered nine or more questions
correctly, you're probably at a C2
level. Well done. And remember to go to
captainenglish.com to improve your
English speaking skills in just two
weeks. As always, thanks for watching
and I'll see you soon.